Guide to the Grace Mott Johnson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Grace Mott Johnson papers
1802-1979
YCAL MSS 622
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
13.77
(35 boxes)
The Grace Mott Johnson Papers are comprised of correspondence, writings, photographs, and personal papers, which document the personal and professional life of the American artist Grace Mott Johnson. The Papers reflect Grace Mott Johnson's involvement in civil rights and involvement in the N.A.A.C.P. The papers also include material pertaining to Grace Mott Johnson's ancestors, including her father Alfred Van Cleve Johnson and grandfather Ebenezer Alfred Johnson. The most prominent correspondents in the papers are Johnson's son Alfred Dasburg and husband Andrew Dasburg.
Johnson, Grace Mott, 1882-1967
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Estate of Alfred V. Dasburg, 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Ebenezer Alfred Johnson Family Papers (MS 1246). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Grace Mott Johnson (1882-1967)
Grace Mott Johnson, sculptor, painter, and civil rights activist, was born to Alfred Van Cleve and Laura Mott Johnson in New York on July 28, 1882. After homeschooling, Johnson attended the New York Art Students League, where she studied with Gutzon Borglum, J.E. Fraser and Hermon MacNeil. While attending the Art Student League's summer school in Woodstock, New York in 1907, Johnson met painter Andrew Dasburg, who she married in 1909. Johnson and Dasburg had one son, Alfred Van Cleve Dasburg, before divorcing in 1922.
Johnson developed a reputation for sculpting animals and would often visit circuses and farms for inspiration. In 1909 Johnson and Dasburg travelled together to Paris, where they befriended a circle of modernist American artists, such as Morgan Russell, Jo Davidson, and Arthur Lee. While in Paris, Johnson exhibited in the Salon des Artistes Francais (1910). Johnson returned to the U.S. and was one of few women to exhibit in the New York Armory Show of 1913. Her pieces were also exhibited at the Panama Pacific Expo, San Francisco (1915), Whitney Studio Club (1919, 1922), National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors (1917, 1927, 1935, and 1936), and Augusta Savage Studios (1939).
For the majority of her life Johnson lived in New York, including Yonkers, Woodstock, and Pleasantville, but she also spent some time in Taos, New Mexico (1920s) and Egypt (1924).
Johnson was an early civil rights activist and lifelong member of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.). She became involved in the Playland (Rye, New York) desegregation case in 1935.
Johnson died on March 12, 1967.
Scope and Contents
The Grace Mott Johnson Papers are comprised of correspondence, writings, photographs, and personal papers, which document the personal and professional life of the American artist Grace Mott Johnson. The papers also include material pertaining to Grace Mott Johnson's ancestors, including her father Alfred Van Cleve Johnson and grandfather Ebenezer Alfred Johnson.
Johnson's artistic life is reflected in the Correspondence, Writings, Other Papers, and Printed Material series. The Correspondence series includes a small amount of correspondence pertaining to Johnson's artistic career, such as correspondence with sculptors Jo Davidson and Clarence Oliver La Grone and with art galleries, societies, and art suppliers. The Writings series contains an early notebook (1895) with poems and songs as well as several unidentified manuscripts dating from 1928 to 1950. The Other Papers series includes photographs of Johnson's artwork as well as snapshots of animals at circuses and on farms, which Johnson used as the basis of her sculptural work. Undated snapshots also capture Johnson's experience at the New York Art Students League. Catalogues and exhibition notices of Johnson's shows can be found in the Printed Materials series.
Correspondents reflect Grace Mott Johnson's involvement in civil rights, and include prominent N.A.A.C.P. leaders such as Charles H. Houston, Walter White, and Roy Wilkins, as well as Elmer Carter (editor of Opportunity ). Further correspondence regarding Johnson's civil rights work can be found in the Other Papers series.
The papers also shed light into the history of the Johnson and Van Cleve families. The most prominent correspondents in the papers are Johnson's family members, such as her son Alfred Dasburg, husband Andrew Dasburg, and the Johnson and Van Cleve families. The Johnson and Van Cleve family papers contain financial records and documents regarding genealogy. Portraits of Johnson and Van Cleve family members are located in the Other Papers series. Printed Material similarly pertains to activities of the Johnson and Van Cleve families.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1840-1977. II. Writings, 1895-1940. III. Other Papers, 1802-1979. IV. Printed Material, 1829-1957.
Civil rights -- United States; Civil rights workers -- United States; Sculptors -- United States -- Archives; Women artists -- United States; Women civil rights workers -- United States; Photographs; Sculptors -- United States -- 20th Century; Dasburg, Andrew, 1887-1979; Johnson, Alfred Van Cleve, 1847-1938; Johnson, E. A. (Ebenezer Alfred), 1813-1891; Johnson, Grace Mott, 1882-1967; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
- Correspondence, 1840-1977; Series I; 6.68; (17 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into five subseries: Outgoing Correspondence, Incoming Correspondence, Alfred Dasburg Correspondence, Andrew Dasburg Correspondence, and Johnson and Van Cleve Family Correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence series documents the personal and professional life of Grace Mott Johnson. The series also includes correspondence relating to her son Alfred Dasburg, her husband Andrew Dasburg, and her ancestors, the Johnson and Van Cleve families.
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Tete-Ansá, Winfried, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Berkeley Express Co., 1939 (Box 1)
    - Biles, Editor of the Pleasantville Townsman, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Brill, Dr. A., 1935-1939 (Box 1)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Crist, J.H., 1933 (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, 1913-1928 (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1908-1925 (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1926 January-May (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1926 June-December (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1928 January-April (Box 2)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1928 May-December (Box 2)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1929 January-June (Box 2)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1929 July-December (Box 2)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1930 (Box 2)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1931 January-June (Box 3)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1931 July-December (Box 3)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1932 January-April (Box 3)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1932 May-December (Box 3)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1933 January-April (Box 4)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1933 April-December (Box 4)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1934-1935 (Box 4)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1939-1949 (Box 5)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1950-1960 (Box 5)
    - Dasburg, Diana, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Dasburg, Matilda, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Doty, Alfred, 1904-1948 (Box 6)
    - Drew, Aileen, 1940 (Box 6)
    - Force, Juliana, 1932-1934 (Box 6)
    - Geiger, Marcia, 1945-1946 (Box 6)
    - Grandmother, undated (Box 6)
    - Heights, Elwyn, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
    - Houghton, Morris and Polly, 1950-1953 (Box 6)
    - Isler, Jacques, 1933 (Box 6)
    - Johnson, E.A., 1887-1888 (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Fanny, 1896-1916 (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Francis, 1936-1950 (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Mark, 1929-1953 (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Van Cleave, 1938-1939 (Box 6)
    - Kerr, Howard, 1933 (Box 6)
    - Lee, Arthur, 1935-1952 (Box 6)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1933 (Box 6)
    - McBean, Atholl, 1939 (Box 6)
    - N.A.A.C.P., 1933-1939; 2 (Box 6)
    - Pittsburgh Courier, 1934 (Box 6)
    - Sanger, Margaret, 1939 (Box 6)
    - Sholtz, David, 1935 (Box 6)
    - Sutherland, Mr., 1939 (Box 6)
    - Vann, Robert L., 1939 (Box 6)
    - Wainwright, Mrs., 1946 (Box 6)
    - Webb, Mr., 1928 (Box 6)
    - Wiegand, Margaret, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Williams, Charles, copy of lease, 1939 (Box 6)
    - Empty envelopes addressed to Grace Mott Johnson by Grace Mott Johnson, 1950-1952 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified, 1939-1953 (Box 6)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Tete-Ansá, Winfried, 1932-1939 (Box 7)
    - Bercinsky, Dr. D., 1914 (Box 7)
    - Blaisdell, R.E., 1938 (Box 7)
    - Blechner, Mrs. George, 1953 (Box 7)
    - Boyurt, A.B., 1936 (Box 7)
    - Brandenburgh, Margaret, 1917-1949 (Box 7)
    - Brill, A. A. (Abraham Arden), 1934-1939 (Box 7)
    - Butler, Roy, Lora, and Betty, 1938-1952 (Box 7)
    - Cahen, E., 1906 (Box 7)
    - Carter, Elmer A. (Elmer Anderson), 1930 (Box 7)
    - Clark, James L., 1929 (Box 7)
    - Collins, Ruth, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Chisholm, Margaret, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Copeland, Royal S., 1934 (Box 7)
    - Crawford Family, 1952 (Box 7)
    - D'Andrea, Cecile, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1919-1940s; 3 (Box 7)
    - Dasburg, Alfred, 1950-1960s; 3 (Box 8)
    - Dasburg, Daffy, 1949-1953 (Box 8)
    - Dasburg, Debbie, 1949-1953 (Box 8)
    - Dasburg, Diana, 1941-1949 (Box 8)
    - Dasburg, Margaret, 1915-1944 (Box 8)
    - Dasburg, Matilda, 1940-1960 (Box 8)
    - Davidson, Jo, undated (Box 8)
    - Dennis, James, 1929-1933 (Box 8)
    - Dill, Augustus Granville, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Drew, Dr. A.L., 1947 (Box 8)
    - Edson, Mr. and Mrs. Hanford, 1908 (Box 8)
    - Edwards, Elizabeth, 1950-1952 (Box 8)
    - Evans and Co., 1944 (Box 8)
    - Fiall, Fannie, 1930-1931 (Box 8)
    - Franks, Walter, 1918 (Box 8)
    - Galdo, Mrs., 1917 (Box 8)
    - Geiger, Clarissa Augusta, 1949 (Box 8)
    - Geiger, Diana (Mrs. Van Cleve Geiger), 1949 (Box 8)
    - Geiger, Marcia, 1940 (Box 8)
    - Geiger, Mary, 1940-1952 (Box 8)
    - Heights, Mrs. Anne B., 1940 (Box 9)
    - Heights, R. Elwyns, 1937-1962; 3 (Box 9)
    - Holden, Stephen and Clarissa, 1952 (Box 9)
    - Houghton, Cecil, 1948-1952 (Box 9)
    - Houghton, Lottie, 1937-1940 (Box 9)
    - Houghton, W.M. (ie. Morris) and Polly, 1950-1952 (Box 9)
    - Houston, Charles H., 1936 (Box 9)
    - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1932 (Box 10)
    - Johnson, Ada Mary, 1940 (Box 10)
    - Johnson, Alfred Doty, 1914-1952 (Box 10)
    - Johnson, Earl, 1950 (Box 10)
    - Johnson, Fanny, 1886-1918; 5 (Box 10)
    - Johnson, Francis, 1918-1952; 2 (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Margaret, 1918-1952 (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Mark, 1932-1953 (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Mary, 1905-1950 (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Van Cleve, 1908-1952; 2 (Box 12)
    - Jones, Lola, 1917 (Box 12)
    - Jutte, Francis Watson, 1952 (Box 12)
    - Kerr, Howard, no year, July 7 (Box 12)
    - Labaree, Mary Fleming, 1930 (Box 12)
    - Lachenbruch, Rachel, 1941-1948 (Box 12)
    - LaGrone, Clarence, 1934 (Box 12)
    - Lee, Arthur, 1952 (Box 12)
    - Lee, Freddie, 1917 (Box 12)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, empty envelope, undated (Box 12)
    - Lujan, J.C., 1920 (Box 12)
    - Maloney, John and Lucia, 1952 (Box 12)
    - Miles, John E., 1938 (Box 12)
    - Minor, Esther T., 1948 (Box 12)
    - McDowells, 1952 (Box 12)
    - McWillie, Elizabeth, 1937-1940 (Box 12)
    - Moody, Pauline, 1952 (Box 12)
    - Moore, Alice, 1931-1953 (Box 12)
    - Moore, Mary, 1937-1953 (Box 12)
    - Morton-Morris, Mattie Sevier, 1940-1951 (Box 12)
    - Mott, John (Grandfather), 1887-1888 (Box 12)
    - Mott, Laura (Grandmother), 1886-1908 (Box 12)
    - Nash, Mary and Vernon, undated (Box 13)
    - Odok, Effiom, 1938-1952 (Box 13)
    - Payton, Dolores, 1940 (Box 13)
    - Ray, V.C., 1917-1953 (Box 13)
    - Reiss, Henrietta Anne, 1917 (Box 13)
    - Rohan, Henry, 1960 (Box 13)
    - Roberts, Ernest, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Rogers, Ralph and Molly, 1950 (Box 13)
    - Sands, R., 1936 (Box 13)
    - Sauer, C.T., 1908 (Box 13)
    - Schuyler, Josephine, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Schuyler, Philippa, signed program, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Seligman, Arthur, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Senior Chair Club, 1950 (Box 13)
    - Slater, Rev. and Mrs. Thomas, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Smith, Joseph, 1949 (Box 13)
    - Spencer, Mr. and Mrs. E.A., undated (Box 13)
    - Steenburgh, Ruth, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Stewart, Dorothy, 1927 (Box 13)
    - Sutton, Alice M., 1940 (Box 13)
    - Tallman, Catherine, 1948-1953 (Box 13)
    - Thomson, Hubert and Alice, 1952 (Box 13)
    - Treasury Dept. (Painting and Sculpture), 1935 (Box 13)
    - Ullah, Lillian, 1938-1940 (Box 13)
    - Van, Isa, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Wagner, Robert, 1934 (Box 13)
    - Wainwright, Grace, 1949-1952 (Box 13)
    - Wardwell, Elsie, 1952 (Box 13)
    - Watkins, Mrs., undated (Box 13)
    - Weekes Brothers, 1916-1948 (Box 13)
    - Wheeler, Miss, 1917 (Box 13)
    - White, Walter, 1935-1952 (Box 13)
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1933-1936 (Box 13)
    - Wright, Corinne, 1952 (Box 13)
    - Zimmerman, J.F., 1933 (Box 13)
    - Various letters from art galleries, societies, and suppliers, 1929-1952; 2 (Box 13)
    - Postcards, 1905-1921 (Box 13)
    - Unidentified, 1911-1953 (Box 13)
  - Alfred Dasburg Correspondence
    - Adams, Dawson, undated (Box 14)
    - Barrett, Sara E., 1926 (Box 14)
    - Blair Galleries, Ltd., 1977 (Box 14)
    - Bond, Marion E., 1931 (Box 14)
    - Brandenburgh, Beulah A., 1926 (Box 14)
    - Brandenburgh, George and Margaret, 1927-1933 (Box 14)
    - Brill, Dr. A., 1935 (Box 14)
    - Buchanan, Sam and Mildred, 1977 (Box 14)
    - Clark, Elizabeth (Betty), 1931-1935; 3 (Box 14)
    - D-Andrea, Paul, 1926 (Box 14)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, 1920-1935 (Box 14)
    - Dasburg, Ann, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Dasburg, Debbie, letters to Dasburg family, 1960 (Box 14)
    - Dasburg, Margaret, 1924-1935; 2 (Box 14)
    - Dasburg, Marina, 1935 (Box 15)
    - Dasburg, Matilda Morton-Morris, 1945 (Box 15)
    - DeVito, Tony, 1929-1930 (Box 15)
    - Dorman, John, 1926-1930 (Box 15)
    - Eastman, Dan, 1928-1931 (Box 15)
    - Field, John A., 1921-1926 (Box 15)
    - Fisher, Irene, 1929 (Box 15)
    - Geiger, Mary Johnson, undated (Box 15)
    - Geiger, Van Cleve, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Ginsbourg, Mark, 1933 (Box 15)
    - Hall, E., 1935 (Box 15)
    - Harrison, Caroline, 1931-1933 (Box 15)
    - Houghton, H., 1967 (Box 15)
    - House of Easy Payments, 1931 (Box 15)
    - Howland, Murray, 1931 (Box 15)
    - Hueblein, Francis Louise, 1932-1933 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Alfred Doty and Clara, 1925 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Fanny, 1913-1916 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Francis, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, James S., 1926 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Juanita Joy, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Van Cleve, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Kauffman, F. Lane, 1930 (Box 15)
    - Lane, Mrs. Franklin K., 1935 (Box 15)
    - Lane, Nancy, 1928-1935 (Box 15)
    - Law(?), Betty, 1933 (Box 15)
    - M., E., 1931-1933 (Box 15)
    - Macomb, Edith H., 1928 (Box 15)
    - Macy and Co., 1928 (Box 15)
    - McKellar, Douglas, 1967 (Box 15)
    - McKellar, Margaret, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Miller, Ernest and Leola, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Moore, Alice, 1967 (Box 15)
    - N.A.A.C.P., 1952 (Box 15)
    - Pitcher, Otto Mears, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Proske, Beatrice Gilman, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Quincy, Mary Louise, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Randolph, Lee and Marva, 1967 (Box 15)
    - St. Paul's Episcopal Church, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Schwalbe, Dinny Dasburg, 1967 (Box 16)
    - Shonnard, Eugenie F., undated (Box 16)
    - Somerville, Iliane and Margaret, 1967 (Box 16)
    - Spon and Chamberlain, 1926 (Box 16)
    - Stanford University, 1930 (Box 16)
    - Stevens, Phoebe, 1930 (Box 16)
    - Stevens, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Wood, 1932 (Box 16)
    - Stolls, Frederic, 1931 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous Letters from Elementary School Classmates, 1921-1923 (Box 16)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1926-1967; 2 (Box 16)
    - Various correspondence regarding family history, 1950-1958; 2 (Box 16)
      Includes notes on family history
  - Andrew Dasburg Correspondence
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, empty envelope, 1952 (Box 16)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1946 (Box 16)
    - Postcards, 1909 (Box 16)
  - Johnson and Van Cleve Family Correspondence
    - Johnson, Alfred Van Cleve from Fanny Johnson, 1876-1895 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Alfred Van Cleve from various correspondents, 1878-1903 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Ebenezer Alfred from Alfred Van Cleve Johnson, 1875-1889 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Ebenezer Alfred from various correspondents, 1861-1878 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from Alfred Doty and Cora Johnson, 1917-1919 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from Alfred Van Cleve Johnson, 1864-1880 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from Mary Johnson and Edward Calhoun Geiger, 1905-1917 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from Margaret Fox Van Cleve Johnson, 1880 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from Van Cleve Johnson, 1919 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Frances (Fanny) Henrietta from various correspondents, 1887-1918 (Box 17)
    - Johnson, Margaret Van Cleve from various correspondents, 1840-1849 (Box 17)
    - Millie from Cousin Grace, 1879 (Box 17)
- Writings, 1895-1940; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series II is arranged chronologically.
  The series is comprised of Grace Mott Johnson's writings from roughly 1895 to 1950, in addition to writings she was particularly interested in and inspired by.
  - Notebook of Poems and Songs, 1895 (Box 18)
  - Unidentified manuscripts, 1928-1950; 4 (Box 18)
  - "Marian Anderson Voice of America" and "Exams in Rhyme for Adult Education U.S.A.," printed versions, 1939 (Box 18)
  - Works by others copied in Grace Mott Johnson's hand, 1940 (Box 18)
- Other Papers, 1802-1979; Series III; 5.01; (13 boxes)
  Series III is organized into three subseries: Personal Papers, Johnson and Van Cleve Family Papers, and Photographs.
  The Other Papers series contains Grace Mott Johnson's personal papers, such as diaries, financial records, business records, and material relating to exhibitions. The series also includes papers relating to Grace Mott Johnson's ancestors (the Johnson and Van Cleve families). The Photographs subseries is comprised of formal portraits of Grace Mott Johnson and Johnson and Van Cleve family members. Johnson's snapshots are also included in the Photograph subseries; these include photographs of travels, friends, and family, as well as circus and farm animals, the latter of which informed her sculptural work.
  - Personal Papers
    - Grace Mott Johnson
      - Diaries, 1896-1938; 9 (Box 19)
      - Exhibition labels, lists of pieces on exhibit, prices, and exhibit entry cards, 1929-1949 (Box 20)
      - Business and financial correspondence, wills, statements, and cancelled checks, 1907-1967; 2 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence, notes, and ephemera regarding the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.), Tom Johnson trial, and other material relating to civil rights, 1933-1934 (Box 20)
      - Passport, 1923 (Box 20)
      - Wills, obituary, and other material relating to Grace Mott Johnson's death, 1934-1967 (Box 20)
    - Alfred Van Cleve Dasburg
      - "Notes on the day", 1928 (Box 20)
      - "El Conquistador" yearbook, 1929 (Box 20)
    - Andrew Dasburg
      - Clippings, 1957-1976 (Box 20)
      - Ephemera pertaining to Dasburg's 90th Birthday Party, 1977 (Box 20)
      - Guestbook from Dasburg's Memorial Service, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Johnson and Van Cleve Family Papers
    - Johnson family papers, 1887-1894, undated (Box 21)
    - Van Cleve family papers, 1833-1835 (Box 21)
    - Alfred Van Cleve Johnson papers, 1862-1884 (Box 21)
    - Assignment of mortgage belonging to Ebenezar Alfred Johnson, 1853 (Box 21)
    - Will and inventory for Frances (Fanny) Henrietta Johnson, 1912-1920 (Box 21)
    - Family trees and history, undated (Box 21)
    - Records of births and deaths removed from Bible, 1802-1851 (Box 21)
    - Bills of fare, 1851 (Box 21)
    - Clippings and printed material collected by Van Cleve and Johnson family members, 1844-1938 (Box 21)
  - Photographs
    - Portraits of Grace Mott Johnson, 1901, undated; 2 (Box 22)
    - Europe, 1909-1910 (Box 22)
    - Livestock and agricultural fair, 1911-1921, undated (Box 22)
    - Circus, 1917-1923; 2 (Box 22)
    - Summer and miscellaneous, 1918 (Box 22)
    - New Mexico and New York, 1918-1921; 2 (Box 22)
    - Bal. Stated, 1919 March (Box 22)
    - Grace Mott Johnson, 145 Trenchard Street, Yonkers, New York, 1920 (Box 22)
    - Yonkers, New York, 1920 (Box 22)
    - Cora and Verel from Coatesville, PA., 1920 (Box 22)
    - Taos, New Mexico, 1921 (Box 22)
    - Collier's effigy, New Mexico, undated (Box 22)
    - New Mexico, undated; 2 (Box 23)
    - Elephants, Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey, Newark, New Jersey, 1921-1922 (Box 23)
    - Egypt, 1923; 4 (Box 23)
    - Yonkers, New York, 1923 (Box 23)
    - Maverick Festival, 1923 (Box 23)
    - Cats and Alfred, Yonkers, New York, 1924 (Box 23)
    - Santa Fe and Taos, New Mexico, 1926; 3 (Box 23)
    - Florida, 1926 (Box 23)
    - Mariska and friends, Woodstock, New York, 1926-1927 (Box 24)
    - Circus, 1929 (Box 24)
    - Lincoln University track meet and Elise Leito Norma, 1929; 2 (Box 24)
    - Philippa and Josephine Schuyler, Rye beach, Isler, and J. Duke, 1931-1932; 3 (Box 24)
    - Circus, Florida, New Haven, Connecticut, 1931; 3 (Box 24)
    - Portrait of Heights, 1934 (Box 24)
    - Art class, undated (Box 24)
    - Boston, Massachusetts, undated (Box 24)
    - Woodstock, New York, undated (Box 24)
    - Woodstock, New York, Cimarron and Taos, New Mexico, undated (Box 24)
    - N.A.A.C.P. Houstons Playlang (?), undated (Box 24)
    - The Helping Hand Baby and motto, undated (Box 24)
    - Mrs. Alma McNeal and Virginia Outley, undated (Box 24)
    - Plainfield, New York, World's Fair, undated (Box 24)
    - San Francisco, California, undated (Box 24)
    - Farmstead, undated (Box 24)
    - Zoological park animals, Central Park, New York, undated (Box 24)
    - Oregon, undated (Box 24)
    - Athens, Winstead, B & O, undated (Box 24)
    - Unsuccessful prints of card photos, undated (Box 24)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 24)
    - Alfred Van Cleve Dasburg and family, 1911-1960s; 9 (Box 25)
    - Alfred Van Cleve Dasburg and family, 1950s-1970s; 12 (Box 26)
    - Photograph album of Johnson and Geiger family farmstead, 1914-1920, undated (Box 27)
    - Photograph album of Johnson and D'Andrea family on farmstead, 1915-1917, undated (Box 27)
    - Photograph album of ranch, undated (Box 27)
    - Portraits of Johnson family, undated (Box 28)
    - Portraits of Johnson and Law families, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Portraits of Johnson and Van Cleve families, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Portraits of Alfred Doty Johnson, 1888 (Box 28)
    - Portraits of Ebenezar Alfred Johnson, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Portrait of Charles Johnson, undated (Box 28)
    - Portrait of Alfred Van Cleve Johnson, undated (Box 28)
    - Portraits of Francis (Fanny) Henrietta Johnson, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Unidentified photographs of ancestors, undated; 4 (Box 28)
    - Unidentified photographs of ancestors, undated; 2 (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, Joe, Clara, slides, undated (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg with others, undated (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, Governor's Gallery show, negatives, undated; 2 (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, Johnsons, work, and Lila Howard, undated (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, work, Lila Howard, Dinny, Beulah, negatives, undated (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, 90th birthday party, 1977; 2 (Box 29)
    - Andrew Dasburg, Tony Lukas at Hacienda de San Roberto, 1977 (Box 29)
    - Blair gallery, 1977 (Box 29)
    - Rochester, undated (Box 29)
    - Nancy, undated (Box 29)
    - New Mexico, undated (Box 29)
    - Germany, 1945 (Box 29)